iupui.edu 2017-10-19

# Privacy Notice: Indiana University–Purdue University Indianapolis

Effective: 2014-11-18

### Applicability

This privacy notice applies only to the Indiana University–Purdue University Indianapolis (IUPUI) website (https://www.iupui.edu) and explains our practices concerning the collection, use, and disclosure of visitor information. Visitor information collected by IUPUI will be used only as outlined in this privacy notice.

Other units at the university may collect and use visitor information in different ways. Therefore, visitors to other university websites should review the privacy notices for the particular sites they visit. IUPUI is not responsible for the content of other websites or for the privacy practices of websites outside the scope of this notice.

### Changes

Because Internet technologies continue to evolve rapidly, IUPUI may make appropriate changes to this notice in the future. Any such changes will be consistent with our commitment to respecting visitor privacy, and will be clearly posted in a revised privacy notice.

### Collection and Use

#### Passive/Automatic Collection

When you view pages on our site, the web server automatically collects certain technical information from your computer and about your connection.

This website is hosted on [Webserve](http://webmaster.iu.edu/account_info/webserve.shtml), a shared web-hosting environment provided by IU’s University Information Technology Services. For more information about privacy practices related to Webserve, read the [Webserve Privacy Notice Supplement](http://webmaster.iu.edu/privacy).

In addition to any information collected by Webserve, our server and/or site collects the following:

  * The domain name from which you visit our site
  * Aggregate information on pages visited
  * The referring website
  * The date and time of visit
  * The duration of visit
  * Your browser type
  * Your screen resolution
  * Aggregregate information collected by Google Analytics

Continued use of our website indicates consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of this information as described in this notice.

Some technical information is retained in aggregate for up to 730 days.

#### Active/Manual/Voluntary Collection

Other than automatically collected technical information about your visit described above, or cookies and anonymous identifiers, described below, we may ask you to provide information voluntarily, such as through forms or other manual input—in order to make products and services available to you, to maintain and manage our relationship with you, including providing associated services, or to better understand and serve your needs. This information is generally retained as long as you continue to maintain a relationship with us. Your providing this information is wholly voluntary. However, not providing the requested information (or subsequently asking that the data be removed) may affect our ability to deliver the products or service for which the information is needed. Providing the requested information indicates your consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of this information as described in this notice. Information we may actively collect could include information volunteered by the visitor, such as preferences, survey information, and/or site registrations.

#### Information Usage

This information is:

  * Used for internal review and then discarded
  * Used to customize the content of our site

#### Information Sharing

We may share aggregate, non-personally identifiable information with other entities or organizations.

We do not share any personally identifiable information (PII) with other entities or organizations, except when legally required to do so, at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our website and applicable laws, or to protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our website.

Except as described above, we will not share any PII with any party for any reason.

Except as provided in the Disclosure of Information section below, we do not attempt to use the technical information discussed in this section to identify individual visitors.

#### Cookies and Anonymous Identifiers

A [cookie](https://kb.iu.edu/data/agwm.html) is a small data file that is written to your hard drive that contains information about your visit to a web page. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you may configure your browser not to accept them at all, or to notify and require approval before accepting new cookies. Some web pages/websites may not function properly if the cookies are turned off, or you may have to provide the same information each time you visit those pages.

In order to customize the information and services offered to you, our site uses cookies to:

  * Customize web page content on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends
  * Record aggregregate information collected by Google Analytics

An anonymous identifier is a random string of characters that is used for the same purposes as a cookie on platforms, including certain mobile devices, where cookie technology is not available.

#### Children

This site is not directed to children under 13 years of age, does not sell products or services intended for purchase by children, and does not knowingly collect or store any personal information, even in aggregate, about children under the age of 13. We encourage parents and teachers to be involved in children’s Internet explorations. It is particularly important for parents to guide their children when they are asked to provide personal information online.

#### Use of Third Party Services

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). It also uses Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, part of a larger category of features known as Google Analytics Advertising Features. Google Analytics uses cookies (described above) to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including possibly your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google.

##### Opting Out of Google Analytics Advertising Features

Users can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads by using [Google Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

For more information, please visit [Google’s Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy).

##### Additional Information Related to the Use of Third Party Services

This website utilizes advertising services provided by [Spongecell](http://www.spongecell.com/), an advertising technology company, contracted by Indiana University. For more information, please visit [Spongecell’s Privacy Policy](https://www.spongecell.com/privacy-policy).

### Disclosure of Information

Other than sharing your information with other appropriate university personnel and units to ensure the quality, functionality, and security of our website, or manage your relationship with us, we will not disclose personally identifiable information about your use of the site except under the following circumstances:

  * With your prior written (including email) consent
  * When we have given you clear notice that we will disclose information that you voluntarily provide
  * With appropriate external parties, such as law enforcement agencies, in order to investigate and respond to suspected violations of law or university policy. Any such disclosures shall comply with all applicable laws and university policies.

### Security

Due to the rapidly evolving nature of information technologies, no transmission of data over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. While we are committed to protecting the privacy of our visitors, we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to university websites, and you do so at your own risk. However, once we receive your information, we will use reasonable safeguards consistent with prevailing industry standards and commensurate with the sensitivity of the data being stored to maintain the security of that information on our systems.

In addition, we will comply with all applicable federal, state, and local laws regarding the privacy and security of visitor information.

We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.

### Privacy Notice Changes

From time to time, we may use visitor information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice.

Only data collected from the time of the policy change forward will be used for these new purposes. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our website periodically.

### Contact Information

If you have questions or concerns about this policy, please contact us via email at webteam@iupui.edu.

If you feel that this site is not following its stated policy and communicating with the owner of this site does not resolve the matter, or if you have general questions or concerns about privacy or information technology policy at Indiana University, please contact the chief privacy officer through the University Information Policy Office, 812-855-UIPO, privacy@iu.edu.
